A Finding Aid to the Ankrum Gallery Records, circa 1900-circa 1990s, bulk 1960-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ankrgall
Archives of American Art
- Morris Broderson Papers, 1941-1989; Series 12; 7.2 Linear feet Box 34-42
  12.8: Financial Material, circa 1960s-circa 1990s
  12.9: Printed Material, circa 1960s-circa 1980s
  12.10: Photographs, 1941-circa 1980s
  12.11: Artwork, 1983
  This series documents Morris Broderson’s professional relationship with his aunt Joan Ankrum and the Ankrum Gallery as his primary art dealer. Materials include biographical materials, correspondence with Joan Ankrum, collectors and clients, publicity files and advertising, travel files, project files, exhibition files, collector/client files, financial material, printed material, photographs, and artwork.
  - Biographical Material, 1961-1989; 12.1
    This subseries includes resumes material and biographical writings and notes by Morris Broderson and others.
    - Biographical Material, 1961-1989 (Box 34, Folder 11-12)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1986; 12.2
    Included here is general correspondence to and from clients and collectors, notes on Morris Broderson written by others, and correspondence with Broderson's lawyer, Sheldon Andelson.
    - General Correspondence and Notes, 1951-1986 (Box 34, Folder 13-17)
    - “Maxine’s Notes on Morris”, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence with Sheldon Andelson, 1972-1973 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Publicity Files, circa 1960s-1988; 12.3
    Found here are materials relating to advertising and Broderson's public persona as an artist. Files include general publicity, "Art in America," and the Los Angeles Art Page among others.
    - General Publicity, circa 1960s-1988 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - “Art in America”, 1965-1970 (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Art Leaders, 1979-1981 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Los Angeles Art Page, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Marquis Who’s Who in America, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Travel, circa 1961-1970; 12.4
    Found here are materials reflecting Morris Broderson's travels to other cities and countries for various projects, art exhibitions, and inspiration. Materials may include sketches, correspondence, flyers and brochures, plane tickets, and a notebook written during his trip to Japan.
    - General Travel, 1961-1970 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Trip to Europe, circa 1961-1968 (Box 35, Folder 5-6)
    - Trip to Japan, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Trip to Japan, Notebook, circa 1962 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Trip to New York, 1966-1970 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Trip to San Diego, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Project Files, 1963-1989; 12.5
    Project files include materials related to special events and projects in which Morris Broderson took part, such as the Watts Benefit, Deaf Arts Conference, and the publication, Art and the Law, among others.
    - Container Corporation Commission, 1963-1966 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Watts Benefit, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 12-13)
    - Lithographs, 1973-1982 (Box 35, Folder 14-15)
    - “Anne Frank”, 1977-1989 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Art and the Law, “The West Collection”, 1979-1986 (Box 35, Folder 17-18)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1982-1984 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Deaf Arts Conference, “What Is Sound”, 1982-1985 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Statue of Liberty, Ellis Island Foundation, Inc., 1986 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition Files, 1961-1994; 12.6
    Exhibiton files include materials on various solo and group exhibitions, such as "Morris Broderson Retrospective" (1975) and "Heart/Hand/Eye" (1986) among others.
    - Ankrum Gallery Exhibitions (circa 1960s), circa 1972-circa 1979 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - “Morris Broderson Retrospective” (1975), circa 1975-1976 (Box 35, Folder 23-25)
    - “American Watercolor” (1979), 1976-1989 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - “Bette Davis Eyes” (1981) (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - “Heart/Hand/Eye” (1986), circa 1972-1986 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - “Recent Paintings” (1986), 1986-1987 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Rochester Institute of Technology Show (1986, 1993), 1984-1994 (Box 35, Folder 30-31)
    - Various Exhibitions (1961-1967), circa 1961-1967 (Box 35, Folder 32-33)
    - Various Exhibitions (1977-1986), 1977-1989 (Box 36, Folder 1-3)
  - Collector and Client Files, 1960-1990; 12.7
    Collector and client files may include materials relating to various individuals, museums, associations, and businessess that sold or purchased Morris Broderson's works of art, incuding the Carnegie Institute, Guggenheim Museum, Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, and Staempfli Gallery, among others.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - California College of Arts and Crafts, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1961-1963 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Ching, William, 1969-1973 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Couturier Gallery, 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - De Young Memorial Museum, 1960-1962 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Downtown Gallery, 1962-1975 (Box 36, Folder 9-11)
    - Fresno Art Museum, 1987-1989 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Fried, Edith, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Gallaudet College, 1979-1984 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Guggenheim Museum, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Halpern, Nathan and Edith, 1970-1984 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Hess, Fritz, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Gold, Herbert, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, 1968-1987 (Box 36, Folder 19-20)
    - Hunt Institute for Botanical Documentation, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Lawrence-Myden Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 1962-1981 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - National Academy of Design, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Palmer Museum of Art, 1983-1992 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - San Diego Museum of Art, 1969-1982 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1980-1981 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Schwab Rehabilitation Center, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Semere, Mario, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Staempfli Gallery, 1969-1990 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Staniek, Eric, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - UCLA Art Council, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - University of Arizona, circa 1975 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Weatherspoon Art Gallery, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1961-1967 (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - Young, John, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - Various Collectors/Clients, circa 1960-1988 (Box 36, Folder 37-38)
  - Financial Material, circa 1960s-circa 1990s; 12.8
    Financial material includes income tax materials, such as receipts and bills, invoices and sales, expenses, and price lists.
    - Income Tax Material, 1965-1987 (Box 37, Folder 1-12)
    - American Photocopy Invoices, 1965-1970 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Invoices and Receipts, Books, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Invoices and Sales, 1961-1976 (Box 37, Folder 15-23)
    - Invoices and Sales, circa 1960s-1990 (Box 38, Folder 1-14)
    - Expenses, 1962-1986 (Box 38, Folder 15-20)
    - Prices, circa 1960s-circa 1990s (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Printed Material, circa 1960s-circa 1980s; 12.9
    Printed material includes exhibition materials, general printed material, clippings, and reviews.
    - Exhibition Materials, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Exhibition Materials, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
    - General Printed Material, 1960-1986 (Box 39, Folder 4-9)
    - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1960s-1975 (Box 39, Folder 10-12)
    - Periodicals, 1960-1979 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Reviews, 1960-1986 (Box 39, Folder 14-17)
    - Oversized General Printed Material from Box 39, Folders 4-9 (Box 41)
  - Photographs, 1941-circa 1980s; 12.10
    Found here are photographs, slides, and negatives of Morris Broderson's works of art, as well as of the artist himself. Also included are unbound, loose portfolio materials of Broderson's artwork.
    - Photographs of Morris Broderson, circa 1941-1987 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - List of Photographs of Artwork, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 20-22)
    - Photographs of Artwork, 1954-circa 1990s (Box 40, Folder 1-18)
    - Portfolio of Photographs of Artwork (unbound), circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 40, Folder 19-24)
    - Negatives of Artwork, circa 1970s (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Artwork, 1983; 12.11
    This subseries includes one original painting by Morris Broderson.
    - Artwork, Painting, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 25)